

Q Search









Messaging Noti



LaVaughn Henry, PhD, CBE · 3rd

Senior Economist at Council of Economic Advisers, Executive Office of the President

Washington, District of Columbia, United States ·

500+ connections · Contact info



Council of Econo Advisers, The Wh



Harvard Universit

Highlights

Reach out to LaVaughn for...

Probono consulting and volunteering, Joining a nonprofit board.

Message LaVaughn

About

Accomplished senior executive with 20+ years of diverse experience in the fields of business economics consulting/advisory services, interest rate and market risk modeling, and government affairs. Strong lea exceptional history of delivering results based on seasoned insight, analytical rigor, and knowledge .

Featured



Article: Addressing Students and Faculty at Rockhurst University - 2012

rockhurst.edu

Cincinnati Fed VP comes back home to RockhurstFebruary 21, 2012 In this electio...



Video: Keynote Address on "The Importance of Improving Your Financial... YouTube

Northern Kentucky NAACP | Martin Luther King Day Luncheon | January 20, 2014 "T...

Activity

1,482 followers



Thanks, my friend. Looking forward to returning to FDIC. Hey

LaVaughn replied to a comment



Thank you so much, my friend. Your words are really appreciated. Yes, we...

LaVaughn commented



Gracias, mi amigo. Como es familia?

LaVaughn replied to a comment



Thanks, Andre. Hope that a with you.

LaVaughn replied to a comment

Experience

C



Senior Economist

Council of Economic Advisers, The White House Oct 2019 – Present · 11 mos

Washington, DC

Analyze economic developments and policy options in the areas of banking, housing, and education. Contributed to the drafting of the 2020 Economic Report of the President.



Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC)

3 yrs 8 mos

Banking and Regulatory Policy Analyst

Jan 2017 – Present \cdot 3 yrs 8 mos Washington D.C. Metro Area

Assist in the interpretation, analysis, proposal and drafting of policy guidelines, existing and proposed statutes and regulations, and studies, including the Federal Deposit Insurance Ac FDIC rules and regulations, the National Bank Act, and other relevant depository institution

... see n











Acting Chief of the Economic Analysis Section (detailee)

Jun 2018 – Aug 2018 · 3 mos Washington D.C. Metro Area

In the absence of the permanent Chief of the Economic Analysis section, managed a team $\mathfrak c$ economists in the drafting and publication of various in-house economic publications and analysis. Served as an economic advisor to the Director and Deputy Director of the Division Insurance and Research. Upon completing the detail, drafted a Strategic Opportuni ... see n

Show 1 more role >



Vice President and Sr. Regional Officer, Cincinnati Branch

Federal Reserve Bank of Cleveland

Aug 2009 – Jul 2016 · 7 yrs Cincinnati, OH

• Serve as senior executive branch leader to 140+ employees operative in the banking supervision, cash management, law enforcement, facilities management, and community development

... see n











Sr. Director, Market Economics and Risk Analysis

PMI Mortgage Insurance Co.

Aug 2006 – Aug 2009 · 3 yrs 1 mo Walnut Creek, CA

o In coordination with the Chief Economist & Strategist, counsel the senior leadership of the corporation on the status of, and outlook for the U.S. housing and mortgage markets, and t development of company risk management policies.

o Manage a diverse team of economic, risk management, and computer programmi ... see n





Director, Midwest Regional Communications

Fannie Mae

 $2003 - 2006 \cdot 3 \text{ yrs}$ Chicago, IL

o Led in the development and implementation of Fannie Mae's communications and policy outreach strategies for the states of Illinois, Indiana, Ohio, Michigan, Wisconsin, Minnesota, North Dakota, South Dakota, Nebraska and Iowa.

o Worked closely with Members of Congress and their staff in the development and \dots see n



Ford Motor Company

4 yrs 8 mos

Assistant Regional Manager, Government Affairs

Oct 1999 – Jan 2002 · 2 yrs 4 mos Chicago, IL

Served as corporate spokesperson and legislative lobbyist in selected states across the Up Midwest. Advised senior leadership on strategies and tactics to influence legislative and regulatory initiatives potentially affecting the company's business and market opportunities

... see n

Senior Policy Economist

Jun 1997 – Sep 1999 \cdot 2 yrs 4 mos Dearborn, MI

Developed economic projections and analysis of motor vehicle sales, industry trends, and c industry issues for the Corporate Economics and Strategics Issues group.

Analyzed regulatory policy issues as they were affected by issues relating to CAFE: ... see n



Financial Economist

Federal Housing Finance Agency
Mar 1994 – Jun 1997 · 3 yrs 4 mos
Washington D.C.

o Supervised the activities of external consultants in the design, development, and implementation of an econometric and statistically based interest rate, cost of funds and m family mortgage loss severity computer simulation module for a risk-based capital regulato standard for Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac. Supported the company's policy researc ... see n



Consulting Manager, Management Science and Economics Group

PwC

Jan 1991 – Jan 1994 · 3 yrs 1 mo Washington, DC

Managed a six-person consulting team tasked with performing annual economic studies of financial soundness of the Federal Housing Administration (FHA) Mutual Mortgage Insurance Fund. Assisted Partners and various Senior Managers in leveraging the existing business relationship with FHA to generate new consulting engagements with other federal ε ... see n

Economist

Resolution Trust Corporation 1990 – 1991 · 1 yr



Senior Economist, Budget Committee

U.S. House of Representatives Aug 1989 – Sep 1990 · 1 yr 2 mos Washington, DC

Provided economic analysis on issues relating to budget bills falling under the authorization the House Banking and Financial Services, and the House Agriculture Committee to the minority Congressional Membership of the Budget Committee. Worked jointly with member the majority staff, and CBO personnel, in analyzing the budgetary implications of va... see n

Show 1 more experience ✓ Show fewer experiences ∧

Education



Harvard University

Doctor of Philosophy (PhD), Economics

1987 - 1991

Activities and Societies: Harvard Kennedy School, Institute of Politics, Student Advisory Committee Harvard Graduate School of Arts and Sciences, Graduate Student Council

- * Wrote doctoral dissertation entitled "Evidence on the Determination, Use, and Risk Implications of Covenants in Debt Contracts"
- * Specialized in the areas of Business Economics, Industrial Organization, and Finance
- * Took courses jointly at Harvard Dept of Economics and MIT's Business School



Harvard University

Master of Arts (M.A.), Economics

1985 - 1987

Activities and Societies: GSAS Graduate Student Council, Institute of Politics Student Advis Committee

- * Taught undergraduate course in Micro and Macroeconomics (Ec 10) under the leadership Drs. Martin Feldstein and Lawrence Lindsey.
- * Served as President of the Graduate School of Arts and Sciences Graduate Student Coun.
- * Served as Graduate School Representative to the Kennedy School of Government's Institute of Politics, Student Advisory Committee



Rockhurst University

Bachelors of Arts, Finance Economics

1982 - 1984

Activities and Societies: Alpha Phi Alpha Fraternity Inc., Alpha Sigma Nu Jesuit Academic H Society

- * Graduated with Honors and received fellowships to multiple Ivy League universities to stugraduate economics
- * Interned at the IBM Corporation while completing undergraduate degree (1982-1983)

Show 1 more education >

Licenses & Certifications

Certified Business Economist

National Association for Business Economics (NABE) Issued Oct 2015 · No Expiration Date

See credential

Volunteer Experience

Board Member

National Association for Business Economics (NABE) Foundation

Sep 2019 – Present • 1 yr

Education

Vice Chair of the of the GSAS Alumni Council Graduate Student Life Committe

Harvard University Graduate School of Arts and Sciences

May 2013 - Present • 7 yrs 4 mos

Education

Served previously as a member of the Graduate Careers Committee (2013-2017); member the Interim Governance Committee (2017-2018); and Vice Chair of the Graduate Student Li Committee (2018-Present)



National Association for Business Economics (NABE) Oct 2018 – Mar 2019 • 6 mos

Education

Served previously as a Member of the Board Of Directors (2013-2016); Chair of the Certific Business Economist (CBE) Development Committee (2017-2019); and Vice Chair of the 201 Policy Conference Steering Committee (2018-2019).

Show 4 more experiences ✓





